Osneil Drakes

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Details

+44 74274 628 46 osneil-drakes@hotmail.com

Links

Github

Linkedin

Skills

MySQL

Node.js

HTML & CSS

React

Git

JavaScript

Ruby

Python

Django

Rails

Hobbies

NFL Fantasy Football Podcasts Art Galleries Pub Quizzes

Profile

Former chartered tax advisor with 5 years of professional experience. Now a full stack developer well versed in agile practices and test driven development, by way of the Makers Academy boot-camp. Excellent team member with extensive experience of working on large scale-projects and meeting client and team deadlines. I am looking for a challenging role that will help me grow and develop into a better and more well-rounded developer.

Tech Experience

Full Stack Software Engineering Bootcamp (Makers Academy)

JULY 2021 - NOVEMBER 2021

Immersive 12 week full-time software development course, focusing on test driven development, pair programming and Agile practices.

- Core Technologies: JavaScript, Ruby, Rails, React, Sinatra, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Python, Django
- Developed a crypto <u>trading bot</u> allowing users to make automated trades based on preset strategies. Built and tested with Python and Django.
- Created <u>a social media app</u> with posting functionality, built with Rails, PostgresSQL and Bootstrap, tested with Rspec and Capybara.

Work Experience

Tax Consultant, Saffery Champness

MARCH 2017 - AUGUST 2019

- My day to day role varied depending on the client but primarily I provided tax advice to UK and non-UK high net worth individuals, liased with HMRC and foreign tax authorities on behalf of my clients dealing with the UK and overseas tax affairs.
- I also handled my portfolio's administration and regulatory requirements, this often including dealing third parties.
- Finally I led the department's technical analysis of the 2017 legislative changes to the taxation of non-domiciliaries enforced in April 2019.

Co-Founder, The Lada Rally

2017 - 2021

- The Lada Rally was a social enterprise that raised funds to help displaced refugees who had settled in Greece.
- I focused on the logistical side of operations, ensuring all participants had the
 necessary documents for travel throughout Europe and purchases of suitable
 vehicles. Though the focus was on fun, staying safe and compliant was key to
 the the Rally's success.
- Given my financial training I oversaw all annual accounting and tax obligations
 for the enterprise, and also supported my co-founders in sourcing external
 corporate partnerships to support the enterprise. Ben & Jerry's provided
 support through their refugee initiatives.

Tax Consultant, Jeffreys Henry

OCTOBER 2020 - JULY 2021

Tax Associate. Grant Thornton

AUGUST 2015 - MARCH 2017

Education

History, University of Kent at Canterbury

SEPTEMBER 2011 - AUGUST 2014

Graduated with first class honours, receiving the 'Final Year Best History Dissertation' prize.